games.com 2003-06-03

# Atari

_Privacy Policy Effective as of_ _5/7/03_

[](http://www.esrb.org/confirm/Infogrames-confirmation.htm)**Atari’s Online Privacy Policy**  
Atari is very concerned with the privacy rights of our online visitors and customers and is committed to protecting the information collected about you. We have adopted an Online Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, store and use the information you provide while visiting any of the websites governed by this Privacy Policy (as listed below). For our information collection practices with respect to children under 13, please see our special children's section below. 

This Privacy Policy and the certification seal located on this page confirm that Atari is a valid licensee and participating member in the Entertainment Software Rating Board's Privacy Online Program: ESRB Privacy Online. To protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative and all of our Web sites have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Online to meet established online information collection and use practices. As part of this privacy program, we are subject to frequent audits of our sites and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by the ESRB.

**Whenever you visit a Website that displays the ESRB Privacy Online Certification Seal, you can expect to be notified of the following:**

  * The websites and information covered by this Privacy Policy 
  * Exactly what personal information may be collected and how it will be used 
  * The consequences, if any, resulting from your refusal to provide personal information 
  * Whether Atari uses cookies, tracks IP Addresses or uses other passive means to collect information 
  * Who, if anyone, is collecting your personal information 
  * With whom, if anyone, will your personal information be shared 
  * What choices you have with regard to the use of your personal information 
  * How you can access and, if necessary, change the personal information Atari collects and maintains 
  * What about links to other parties 
  * Whether and how information is collected from Children under 13 
  * How Atari ensures data security, quality, and integrity 
  * Where and how to ask questions or file complaints 

**The websites and information covered by this Privacy Policy:**

This Privacy Policy currently applies to the following Web sites operated by Atari:

In addition, Atari may own several other domain names that point to the websites listed above. From time to time, we may add new websites and will take reasonable steps to update the list. Please note, however, that this Privacy Policy applies only to the websites set forth above, and not to websites operated by our International affiliates (e.g., Atari in France, United Kingdom, Italy, etc.). When you link to these foreign sites or any other sites from a website listed above, their privacy policies will apply. 

Also, please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by Atari online through the sites listed above, not to information that Atari may collect offline.

**What information does Atari collect and how will it be used?**

In order to give you the best experience on our sites, Atari may collect information about you, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. Typically, we may ask a user to submit personal and/or demographic information, and it will usually take the form of either: (1) game-specific or site registration; (2) community registration; (3) technical product support; (4) placement of an order for goods or services in the event Atari launches an online store; (5) sending an e-card to a friend; (6) submitting a question or comment to our webmaster; and/or, (7) personal information submitted in a business capacity (e.g., resumes). The types of information requested for each activity and the way the information is used are detailed by category below. Please note, however, that depending on the Atari website which you are visiting, some of the amenities listed above may not be available. 

Unless noted otherwise, we may also use your personal information collected through one of the means set forth below for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve the products and services we provide you and to better meet your needs. Demographic information is similarly used to tailor our visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying content according to their preferences. 

No matter what method we use to collect information and no matter how we use that information, we will only collect the information deemed reasonably necessary to fulfill your online requests and our legitimate business objectives.

**Game Specific Registration**

Almost all game pages that appear on our sites provide you the opportunity to register to receive the latest news and information about a particular game (i.e., Subscription Center). If you choose to subscribe, you may be prompted to submit personal information such as your full name, home address, phone number and email address. Additionally, we may ask you for some demographic information including your age, gender, the game systems you own, and the types of games you play. The information you provide on this registration form will be used to send you, via email, game news and information tailored to your game and platform preferences. In addition, we may use the information to send you notices that contain additional information, discounts, and offers from Atari, unless you opt out from receiving such notices at the time of registration or at a later time.   
**  
Community Forum Registration**

To register for membership in our online community, we may ask you to provide personal information such as your email address, and to create a username and password. We may also collect demographic information about you, including your occupation, hobbies and interests, and other preferences. The information that you submit to us for this purpose is used to give you access to our community forums and other community features. 

The ability to participate in the community forums by simply logging in is available to only those Web users who have already created a password during an earlier visit to the community registration area of our site. To login as a member, we may ask you to submit your username and password. This information is collected so that you can access and participate in the community forums without having to reregister. 

Please note that whenever you give out personal information in public areas such as on our community forums, that information can be collected and used by people you don't know. While we strive to protect those who wish to participate in these forums, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you post in these areas. When you register for the community forum, you have the option to make your email address inaccessible to other users of the forum.

**Technical Support**

To submit a question or problem to our technical support center using Atari’s email form, you may be asked to provide your first and last name, date of birth, country, state or province, email address, telephone number, the date and location of your purchase, the name of the game in question, the operating system you are having the trouble on, and a description of the problem you are encountering. The information you provide us for this purpose is used to respond to your troubleshooting problem.

**Online Store**

In the event Atari launches an online store for its web users, visitors purchasing goods or services may need to provide a valid credit card number and expiration date, in addition to name, mailing and billing addresses, phone number and e-mail address. In the event that we launch such an online store, we may also ask you to create a password so that when you return to our site, you can easily retrieve your shopping cart by logging in. 

**E-cards**

Web users who wish to send an e-card to a friend or family member may be asked to provide their name and email address, and the name(s) and email address(es) of the person(s) to whom they wish to send the e-card. After we send the E-card, we do not store the collected email addresses or use them for other purposes.

**Email to Webmaster**

Atari may collect and temporarily store personal information that you voluntarily submit to us via email correspondence. For example, Atari provides a link through which an online visitor can send e-mail to our Webmaster addressing any issue a user encounters when using our websites. Any personal information contained in such email is used by Atari for the sole purpose of responding to your questions. Although most e-mail messages are deleted after they are responded to, in certain cases hard copies of or data from certain e-mail correspondence may be kept on file for security purposes. Any such copy or data will also be stored in a secure location, and information from these messages will not be used for marketing purposes.

**Business Capacity**

Atari allows for the online submission of resumes. Personal information collected from resumes will be used solely for the purpose of accepting and evaluating candidate submissions for job postings. Information obtained from resumes may be shared within our company.

Portions of our site may also contain an area where businesses can submit a request to receive corporate or financial information about Atari (e.g., www.atari.com). Any personal information collected from such requests, such as name, email address, and phone number, is used to respond to the specific request and, if you opt-in, is added to our business mailing list. 

Other than as explained above, this Privacy Policy does not apply to personal information gathered through resumes or requests for corporate or financial information.   
**  
What happens if I refuse to provide my personal information?**

Your refusal to submit personal information may limit your ability to participate in some of our activities such as sweepstakes or community forums. However, you do not need to provide personal information to access and browse our Web sites. 

Does Atari use cookies, track IP Addresses or use other passive means to collect information?

Atari uses cookies on its websites. A "cookie" is a small bit of record-keeping information that websites often store on a user's computer. Cookies do not include people's names, e-mail addresses, or other information that is personally identifiable; they are typically used to quickly identify a user's computer and to "remember" things about the user's visit.

Atari also keep tracks of Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for safety and security reasons. An IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer every time you log on to the Internet.

**Who is collecting my personal information?**

The information you submit to our websites is collected by Atari and is used in the manner specified under the section titled "What information does Atari collect and how will it be used?" Contact information for Atari is provided below. 

**With whom does Atari share my personal information?**

It is our policy not to share your personal information with any third parties. However, this policy does not apply when disclosure is required by law enforcement or other government officials in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose you or us to legal liability. In addition, information about our customers, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any bankruptcy, merger, sale, transfer of company assets, or acquisition, if permitted by and done in accordance with applicable law. 

**Can I choose how my personal information is used?**

If you do not want Atari to send you communications about its products and services, you can opt-out from receiving these communications at the time of information collection or by contacting us by phone at (425) 951-7106 or by regular mail at Atari, Inc., 2230 Broadway Avenue, Santa Monica CA 90404, Attn: Customer Database. In addition, along with every communication sent to you, Atari gives you the opportunity to discontinue receiving future communications.

**How do I access my personal information?**

You always have the option to view, correct and/or delete the personal information collected about you and stored in our database. To do so, please take any one of the following steps: 

1\. Send mail to the following postal address:   
Atari, Inc.   
2230 Broadway Avenue,   
Santa Monica, CA 90404 Attn: Customer Database

2\. Call the following telephone number:   
(425) 951-7106 and use our Automated Systems' Main Menu option or speak to a customer service representative. 

**What is Atari’s policy regarding links to third party sites?**

You should be aware that while you are on a website operated by Atari, you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control and for which we are not responsible. Because we cannot guarantee that the privacy policies of these websites meet our high standards and the requirements of the ESRB Privacy Online Program, we recommend that you read the privacy policy of the website to which you link before you submit any personal information.

**Does Atari collect personal information from children under 13?**

 _Collection and Use of Personal Information_

At this time, we collect and store personal information about children under 13 ("children" or "child") only if it submitted by way of our email support page (accessible from the Technical Support area of our site at www.ina-support.com) and is submitted after we've obtained verifiable parental consent. We do not collect personal information from children through our kids' site located at www.funkidsgames.com. On our email support page, we determine who is younger than 13 years old and whether parental consent is required by asking all users seeking technical support help to submit their age (i.e., date of birth). Those users under 13 years old are directed to our Parental Consent Form. If given verifiable permission from a parent, Atari may collect and store the following types of personal information about a child seeking technical support help: first and last name, email address, and telephone number. Atari may also collect demographic information about a child such as the country and state in which the child lives, the child's date of birth, and a description of the hardware (e.g., operating system) and/or product the child has encountered a problem with; and, combine such information with the child's personal information. Atari will only collect this information if it is voluntarily submitted to us by the child. We do not collect personal information about the child through the use of passive collection mechanisms such as cookies. 

The information collected from a child through our email support page is used by Atari for purposes of diagnosing a child's specific technical problem and providing an acceptable solution, and may be stored for purposes of providing ongoing technical support. From time to time and through the use of our email support page, we receive requests from children relating to Frequently Asked Question documents (FAQ's), Hint documents, and/or patch disks or update disks related to a specific game or games, and we may use the contact information provided to respond to such requests. 

Under no circumstances will we ask the child to provide us more personal information than is reasonably necessary for the child to receive technical support help. 

_Third Parties_

Please read the section titled "With whom does Atari share my personal information" (above) for our policy on the disclosure of personal information collected from and about children under 13.

 _Parental Access_

As a parent, you have the right to review, update or delete your child's personal information and/or have Atari discontinue further collection or use of your child's personal information. To do so, please contact us by phone at 425-951-7106, E-Mail ([webmaster@atari.com](mailto:webmaster@atari.com)) or by regular mail at: 

Atari, Inc.

Attn: Technical Support Department  
13110 NE 177th Place  
Suite #B101, Box 180  
Woodinville, WA 98072-9965

We will be happy to review, update, or delete your child's information as appropriate. Please make sure to have your child's email address available for verification purposes.

**What safeguards does Atari use to protect my personal information?**

To protect your personal information, Atari maintains appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the personal information collected from and about its users, including children under 13. Our sites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Personal information collected by Atari is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. 

**How do I ask a question or file a complaint?**

If you have any questions, complaints, or comments regarding our privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with any of our websites, please contact our Technical Support team by phone at (425) 951-7106, or by regular mail at: 

Atari, Inc.  
2230 Broadway Avenue  
Santa Monica, CA 90404  
Attn: Customer Database

For complaints, you can also contact ESRB Privacy Online directly at [www.esrb.org](http://www.esrb.org/) or by regular mail at:

ESRB Privacy Online  
845 Third Avenue  
New York, NY 10022

By using this site, you signify your assent to Atari’s Online Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use this site. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check back from time to time to ensure that you are aware of these changes. Your continued use of this site will signify your acceptance of these changes.

This Privacy Policy reflects the law of the United States. In France, the collection of personal information on the Internet is governed by French law no. 78-17 of January 6, 1978. 

Printable version

|
